const quizQuestions7en = [{
    question:"In FCAW process, when you need to increase the welding current, you should increase:",
    answers: ["the pressure of the wire feeder rollers;",
    "the wire feed speed;",
    "the contact tube-to-work distance;",
    "the arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Pressure regulators and flowmeters are specific to each gas mainly due to the fact that gases have a different:",
    answers: ["density;",
    "thermal conductivity;",
    "ionization potential;",
    "specific pressure."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Why is argon preferred over helium in MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["Argon favours spray-type metallic transfer, which cannot be achieved using helium.",
    "Argon allows for higher welding speeds.",
    "Argon promotes arc voltage growth, thereby increasing the heat generated by the arc.",
    "It favours a better profile of the weld fusion area."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Why is argon preferred over helium in MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["Argon allows for higher welding speeds.",
    "Argon promotes arc voltage growth, thereby increasing the heat generated by the arc.",
    "It favours a better profile of the weld fusion area.",
    "Argon is cheaper than helium."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The gases used in gas shielded arc welding have the following functions:",
    answers: ["Increase the heat input for the same current (valid for some gases only).",
    "Cool the workpiece and the electrode.",
    "Transfer the filler metal to the weld.",
    "Transfer alloy elements to the weld pool."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which cutting process would promote the least amount of distortion?",
    answers: ["Plasma cutting.",
    "Oxi-gas cutting.",
    "Water jet cutting.",
    "Laser cutting."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which process is not suitable for welding steel sheets with thicknesses of less than 1 mm?",
    answers: ["Oxyfuel gas welding (311).",
    "Welding with covered electrodes (111).",
    "GTAW/TIG welding (141).",
    "Resistance spot welding (21)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In MIG/MAG welding, a disadvantage of short-circuiting metal transfer is:",
    answers: ["the impossibility for out of position welding;",
    "a generation of slag inclusions;",
    "a risk of lack of fusion;",
    "the impossibility of welding thin sheets."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the TIG (GTAW) process:",
    answers: ["In TIG welding with helium shielding gas, low arc voltage and greater cleaning effect are produced.",
    "In TIG welding, manual and automatic wire feeding can be used.",
    "TIG welding with alternating current is used for welding austenitic stainless steels.",
    "In TIG welding with filler material feeding, the current value is a consequence of the wire feed speed adjustment."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the TIG (GTAW) process:",
    answers: ["In TIG welding with DCEN polarity, the electric arc is less stable than with DCEP polarity and the electrode suffers excessive wear.",
    "TIG welding with alternating current is used for welding aluminium/magnesium and its alloys.",
    "On TIG welding torches, the ceramic nozzles (cups) should be as smaller as possible to provide adequate shielding gas density.",
    "In TIG welding with helium shielding gas, low arc voltage and greater cleaning effect are produced."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"For which welding process is a constant voltage power source most adequate?",
    answers: ["Flux cored arc welding (FCAW).",
    "TIG (GTAW) welding.",
    "Submerged arc welding (SAW) with thick wires.",
    "Welding with covered electrodes (MMA/SMAW)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"For which welding process is a constant voltage power source most adequate?",
    answers: ["MIG/MAG (GMAW) welding.",
    "TIG (GTAW) welding.",
    "Submerged arc welding (SAW) with thick wires.",
    "Welding with covered electrodes (MMA/SMAW)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"For which welding process is a constant voltage power source most adequate?",
    answers: ["TIG (GTAW) welding.",
    "Submerged arc welding (SAW) with thick wires.",
    "Submerged arc welding (SAW) with small diameter wires.",
    "Welding with covered electrodes (MMA/SMAW)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Pulsed GTAW (TIG Welding) will provide:",
    answers: ["reduced heat affected zone;",
    "increased penetration;",
    "smooth weld bead appearance;",
    "higher deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following gases helps to promote the cleaning action on aluminium when using TIG welding (GTAW)?",
    answers: ["Argon+Helium.",
    "Argon+Hydrogen.",
    "Helium.",
    "Argon."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In pulsed GTAW (TIG welding) the background current:",
    answers: ["melts the filer metal;",
    "maintains the arc;",
    "maintains the penetration;",
    "maintains the width of the weld pool."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In pulsed GMAW (MIG/MAG welding) the background current:",
    answers: ["melts the wire electrode metal;",
    "maintains the arc;",
    "maintains the penetration;",
    "maintains the metal transfer."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is a serious drawback of the GTAW/TIG process?",
    answers: ["It does not allow to deposit the filler metal in overhead position. ",
    "Low thermal efficiency factor (poor use of the heat generated by the arc).",
    "High gas flow rates are needed.",
    "Power sources of the Constant Current type are needed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["There are only few types of material that can be welded.",
    "Being a very slow process, it produces a large heat affected zone (HAZ) in the base metal.",
    "Equipment costs can be higher than in other welding processes.",
    "Porosity is difficult to avoid."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["There are only few types of material that can be welded.",
    "It is difficult to avoid the lack of fusion at the weld root.",
    "Argon, being heavier than air, can accumulate and displace air when welding in confined environments.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["There are only few types of material that can be welded.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized.",
    "It is not economically suitable to weld metals more than 8 mm thick.",
    "Porosity is difficult to avoid."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates.",
    "No spatter is generated.",
    "Higher welding speeds than many other welding processes.",
    "Lower UV radiation than many other welding processes."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Higher welding speeds than many other welding processes.",
    "It allows to weld more metals and metal alloys than any other arc welding process.",
    "No need for good hand-eye coordination skills.",
    "Equipment costs can be lower than in many other welding processes."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Higher welding speeds than many other welding processes.",
    "It is well adequate for welding dissimilar metals.",
    "Equipment costs can be lower than in many other welding processes.",
    "It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Higher welding speeds than many other welding processes.",
    "It's easy to be mechanized or automated.",
    "It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates.",
    "There is no risk of metal inclusions in the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates.",
    "It offers precise control of heat input because the heat source and filler metal feeding are controlled separately.",
    "The shielding gases used are of lower cost.",
    "There is no risk of metal inclusions in the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Higher welding speeds than many other welding processes.",
    "It is a low hydrogen process.",
    "There is no risk of metal inclusions in the weld.",
    "It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates.",
    "The deposited weld metal typically has a shiny appearance and may only require a little brushing between passes.",
    "Higher welding speeds than many other welding processes.",
    "There is no risk of metal inclusions in the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Lower UV radiation than many other welding processes.",
    "This process allows for a more concentrated arc and thus produces a narrow heat affected zone (HAZ) in the base material.",
    "It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates.",
    "There is no risk of metal inclusions in the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["Higher welding speeds than many other welding processes.",
    "By minimizing the HAZ (Heat Affected Zone), this process helps prevent distortion, particularly in thin materials.",
    "There is no risk of metal inclusions in the weld.",
    "It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates.",
    "The low heat generated by this process minimizes the risk of burning in thin materials.",
    "Lower UV radiation than many other welding processes.",
    "There is no risk of metal inclusions in the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["It is very suitable for welding thick metal plates.",
    "There is no metal transfer through the arc, so no spatter is produced and the arc is more stable.",
    "Higher welding speeds than many other welding processes.",
    "Lower UV radiation than many other welding processes."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["It is basically a manual welding process.",
    "Being a very slow process, it produces a large heat affected zone (HAZ) in the base material.",
    "Not suitable for extreme conditions (e.g., winds).",
    "It requires a higher level of skill and dexterity when compared to the GTAW (TIG welding) process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Being a very slow process, it produces a large heat affected zone (HAZ) in the base material.",
    "Unlike GTAW (TIG welding) or SMAW (MMA welding), this welding process is difficult to master.",
    "This process is sensitive to contaminants because it can only withstand low to moderate levels of surface contaminants such as rust, mill scale, dirt, oil and paint.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Being a very slow process, it produces a large heat affected zone (HAZ) in the base material.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized.",
    "Due to the size of the GMAW (MIG/MAG) torch, it is difficult to reach hard-to-reach (confined) areas.",
    "Lower filler metal deposition rate than in many other welding processes."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["There are very limited types of material that can be welded by this process.",
    "Unlike GTAW (TIG welding) or SMAW (MMA welding), this welding process is difficult to master.",
    "The metallurgical action is limited compared to the SMAW (MMA welding) process.",
    "It requires a higher level of skill and dexterity when compared to the GTAW (TIG welding) process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["There are very limited types of material that can be welded by this process.",
    "Being a very slow process, it produces a large heat affected zone (HAZ) in the base material.",
    "A fan (even from the power source itself) can remove the protective atmosphere and cause porosity.",
    "It is not economically suitable to weld metals more than 6 mm thick."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["There are very limited types of material that can be welded by this process.",
    "It is not economically suitable to weld metals more than 6 mm thick.",
    "Welded metal will cool at higher rates as it is not covered by slag when the weld is complete.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["There are very limited types of material that can be welded by this process.",
    "Unlike GTAW (TIG welding) or SMAW (MMA welding), this welding process is difficult to master.",
    "Due to the possibility to weld at low currents, this process can cause lack of fusion when operating in short circuiting mode.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["It is very suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds).",
    "This process allows you to weld thin materials and up to unlimited thickness using multiple passes.",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation.",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint).",
    "Less fumes are produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "It is very suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds).",
    "It is suitable for use in confined spaces."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["It is very suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds).",
    "It can weld many metals and alloys.",
    "No need for good hand-eye coordination skills.",
    "Due to the possibility to weld at any current, this process has no risk to provoke a lack of fusion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Lower UV radiation than many other welding processes.",
    "Low-cost consumables.",
    "Due to the possibility to weld at any current, this process has no risk to provoke a lack of fusion.",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint).",
    "It's easy to be mechanized or automated.",
    "Due to the possibility to weld at any current, this process has no risk to provoke a lack of fusion.",
    "It is very suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Due to the possibility to weld at any current, this process has no risk to provoke a lack of fusion.",
    "High electrode use efficiencies, up to 93% to 97%, unlike SMAW (MMA welding), which has electrode use efficiencies around 65%.",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint).",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["It is very suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds).",
    "It is a low hydrogen process.",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint).",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Due to the possibility to weld at any current, this process has no risk to provoke a lack of fusion.",
    "Unlike GTAW (TIG welding) or SMAW (MMA welding), this welding process is easier to master.",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation.",
    "It is very suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["It is very suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds).",
    "Being a slag-free process, it does not require slag cleaning.",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint).",
    "Due to the possibility to weld at any current, this process has no risk to provoke a lack of fusion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Lower UV radiation than many other welding processes.",
    "It has a high operating factor as there is no need to remove slag and it uses a continuous electrode.",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation.",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Due to the possibility to weld at any current, this process has no risk to provoke a lack of fusion.",
    "It can operate as semi- or fully automatic.",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation.",
    "It is very suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint).",
    "There is very little slag produced, so post-weld clean-up is minimal.",
    "Lower UV radiation than many other welding processes.",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The groove profile of the wire feeder rollers in MIG/MAG welding is:",
    answers: ["V-shaped for welding with steel and aluminium wires;",
    "V-shaped for welding with steel wire and U-shaped for aluminium wire.",
    "U-shaped for welding with steel wire and V-shaped for aluminium wire;",
    "U-shaped for welding with steel and aluminium wires."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["There are very limited types of material that can be welded by this process.",
    "Deposition rates are lower than for manual GTAW (TIG welding).",
    "Unlike GMAW (MIG/MAG welding), this welding process is difficult to master.",
    "It requires a higher level of skill and dexterity when compared to the GTAW (TIG welding) process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Higher UV radiation than in GTAW (TIG welding) and in GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "Not suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds).",
    "The arc is partially hidden and the slag is covering the weld puddle, so welding control in this process is a more difficult compared to GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "Unlike GTAW (TIG welding), this welding process is difficult to master."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Deposition rates are lower than in manual GTAW (TIG welding).",
    "Unlike GTAW (TIG welding), this welding process is difficult to master.",
    "The risk of defects related to slag inclusions is much more pronounced compared to GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "The choice of available covered electrodes is limited."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Higher UV radiation than in GTAW (TIG welding) and in GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "Not suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds).",
    "Unless well taken care of, a defect (such as slag inclusion or insufficient penetration) can occur where welding is restarted with a new electrode.",
    "Unlike GTAW (TIG welding), this welding process is difficult to master."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Welded metal will be cooled at high rates as it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "Unlike GTAW (TIG welding), this welding process is difficult to master.",
    "The range of permissible currents for a given electrode diameter is narrower than in GMAW (MIG/MAG welding) for a given wire size.",
    "Not suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["No need for good hand-eye coordination skills.",
    "The metallurgical action is more pronounced compared to the GMAW (MIG/MAG welding) process.",
    "Less fumes are produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "Due to possibility to weld with any current, there no risk of lack of fusion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["It's easy to be mechanized.",
    "Lower UV radiation than in GTAW (TIG welding) and in GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "Due to possibility to weld with any current, there no risk of lack of fusion.",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation.",
    "Welded metal will cool at slower rates as it is covered by the slag when the weld is complete.",
    "Less fumes are produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Due to possibility to weld with any current, there no risk of lack of fusion.",
    "Well suited for a wide variety of commonly used metals and alloys.",
    "It's easy to be mechanized.",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Due to possibility to weld with any current, there no risk of lack of fusion.",
    "The equipment and knowledge of the art are already widely known in most industrial environments.",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation.",
    "Unlike GMAW (MIG/MAG welding), this welding process is easier to master."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Due to possibility to weld with any current, there no risk of lack of fusion.",
    "Deposition rates are higher than in manual GTAW (TIG welding).",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation.",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Less fumes are produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "There are some special electrodes for cutting/gouging available.",
    "Due to possibility to weld with any current, there no risk of lack of fusion.",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Less fumes are produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "A wide variety of covered electrodes is available on the market.",
    "Unlike GMAW (MIG/MAG welding), this welding process is easier to master.",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint).",
    "This process can be used very well for hard surfacing and other types of surfacing.",
    "Due to possibility to weld with any current, there no risk of lack of fusion.",
    "Welded metal cools down at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the use of shielding gases for TIG welding, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The use of gas mixtures (Ar + He) is always more beneficial to the welding quality than a pure gas.",
    "The type of shielding gas recommended does not depend on the current type (DC or AC) and current polarity.",
    "When welding stainless steel, it is mandatory to use the mixture of argon and helium to ensure the necessary penetration.",
    "Helium (because of its high ionization potential) worsens arc stability, so it is mainly used as a purging gas."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding plasma cutting, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["A preheat pilot arc is used to raise the temperature of the steel to its ignition point for cutting.",
    "The expulsion of the molten metal from the region is done by the high pressure of the plasma jet itself.",
    "Plasma cutting is only used to cut thick steels and non-ferrous metals.",
    "Plasma cutting is not used to cut parts with alloying elements, which produce refractory oxides."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What happens when during the MIG/MAG welding (GMAW) the contact tube distance increases?",
    answers: ["The arc becomes longer.",
    "The deposition rate increases.",
    "The penetration decreases.",
    "The pre-heating of the electrode extension decreases."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When welding aluminium using TIG welding, oxide removal takes place:",
    answers: ["when the high frequency is activated;",
    "during the positive half-cycle of the AC;",
    "in DCEN polarity (direct current electrode negative polarity);",
    "when adding filler metal which contains deoxidizers."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"These are metal transfer modes to be operated in conventional MIG/MAG welding:",
    answers: ["short circuit, globular and short arc;",
    "short circuit, spray and pulsed;",
    "spray arc and globular arc;",
    "short circuit, globular and pulsed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"From the alternatives below, indicate the factor that influences the consumption (melting rate) of the electrode wire in the GMAW (MIG/MAG) process.",
    answers: ["Polarity, value and type of current (AC or DC).",
    "Arc length.",
    "No-load voltage of the power source.",
    "Short-circuit current of the power source."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"From the alternatives below, indicate the factor that influences the consumption (melting rate) of the electrode wire in the GMAW (MIG/MAG) process.",
    answers: ["Arc length.",
    "No-load voltage of the power source.",
    "Chemical composition and extension of the electrode wire.",
    "Short-circuit current from the power source."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following materials cannot be welded by MMA (SMAW) process?",
    answers: ["Structural steel sheets and profiles.",
    "Mo and CrMo steel sheets and profiles.",
    "Thin sheets of Cu and Al.",
    "Stainless steel sheets and profiles."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of these alternatives is a function of the slag produced by the covered electrode?",
    answers: ["To control weld penetration.",
    "To prevent the weld metal from cooling down too quickly.",
    "To provide deoxidizers to the weld pool.",
    "To stabilize the arc."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of these alternatives is a function of the slag produced by the covered electrode?",
    answers: ["To control weld penetration.",
    "To reduce the spatter generation.",
    "To dissolve impurities from the weld pool.",
    "To stabilize the arc."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of these alternatives is a function of the slag produced by the covered electrode?",
    answers: ["To control weld penetration.",
    "To provide deoxidizers to the weld pool.",
    "To stabilize the arc.",
    "To protect the weld metal during cooling from being oxidized by oxygen from the atmosphere."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of these alternatives is a function of the slag produced by the covered electrode?",
    answers: ["To shape the weld and to improve the finishing of the weld.",
    "To control weld penetration.",
    "To reduce the spatter generation.",
    "To stabilize the arc."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0"},
    {
    question:"Gray cast iron has:",
    answers: ["no ductility.",
    "low ductility.",
    "medium ductility.",
    "high ductility."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which element makes cast iron difficult to weld?",
    answers: ["Silicon.",
    "Iron.",
    "Carbon.",
    "Manganese."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"To help reduce stress and cracking during the welding of cast iron, it is necessary to:",
    answers: ["peen the heat affected zone after it cools;",
    "peen the heat affected zone while hot;",
    "cool the weld joint as fast as possible;",
    "peen the weld deposit while still hot."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which type of metal identification test reflects the carbon content?",
    answers: ["Spark test.",
    "Magnetic test.",
    "Chip test.",
    "Flame test."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In MIG/MAG welding (GMAW), a small addition of oxygen to argon will:",
    answers: ["worsen the arc stability;",
    "improve the arc stability;",
    "reduce the penetration;",
    "increase the deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
        question:"Which of the following fully determines the chemical composition of weld metal?",
        answers: ["Filler metal in the form of welding electrode or a consumable wire.",
        "Base metal, filler metal and any metal contained in flux or electrode coating.",
        "For most of the welding processes used nowadays; weld metal is derived essentially from the consumables used",
        "Generally; the remelted base metal."],
        correctAnswer:"1",
        subject:"1"
        },        
    {
    question:"Crevice corrosion in the root area of welded stainless steel pipes is caused by:",
    answers: ["unpassivated parent metal;",
    "lack of care in the groove preparation;",
    "lack of gas backing protection (purge);",
    "too high welding current."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The hardenability of steel when quenching is influenced by:",
    answers: ["the heating speed;",
    "heating method (flame, by induction, ...);",
    "the initial iron content;",
    "the initial carbon content."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The hardenability of steel when quenching is influenced by:",
    answers: ["the heating speed;",
    "heating method (flame, by induction, ...);",
    "the initial iron content;",
    "the presence of alloying elements."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The hardenability of steel when quenching is influenced by:",
    answers: ["the heating speed;",
    "heating method (flame, by induction, ...);",
    "the initial iron content;",
    "the cooling speed."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The time of cooling between 800 ºC and 500 ºC increases with:",
    answers: ["preheat;",
    "larger joint thickness;",
    "higher thermal conductivity of the base metal;",
    "higher welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The time of cooling between 800 ºC and 500 ºC increases with:",
    answers: ["higher heat input;",
    "larger joint thickness;",
    "higher thermal conductivity of the base metal;",
    "higher welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Weld metal hot cracking can be reduced by adding which of the following to the weld metal?",
    answers: ["Carbon.",
    "Phosphorus.",
    "Sulphur.",
    "Manganese."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"High-alloy stainless steels are divided according to their chemical composition and microstructure as follows:",
    answers: ["ferritic and bainitic steels;",
    "ferritic, martensitic, martensitic-austenitic, austenitic, duplex and super duplex steels;",
    "ferritic and perlitic steels;",
    "perlitic and ferritic-perlitic steels."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which are the different types of stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Nickel steels and chromium steels",
    "Magnetic and non-magnetic steels",
    "Ferritic, austenitic, austenitic-ferritic (duplex) and martensitic stainless steels",
    "Austenitic steels and duplex-steels"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What type of welded joints, subject to tensile forces, are more susceptible to lamellar tearing?",
    answers: ["Unalloyed steel butt welds of plates or pipes.",
    "T-joint with full penetration of unalloyed steels.",
    "Butt welds of stainless steels (of any type).",
    "T-Joints with full penetration of austenitic stainless steels."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The objective of the tensile test is to:",
    answers: ["measure some mechanical characteristics of the material;",
    "evaluate the structure of the material;",
    "quantitatively determinate the material chemical composition;",
    "evaluate the fatigue strength of the material."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A backing gas mixture of argon and hydrogen is suitable for welding of:",
    answers: ["martensitic stainless steel;",
    "austenitic stainless steel;",
    "ferritic stainless steel;",
    "ferritic-austenitic (duplex) stainless steel."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The gas outlet of the backing argon and argon mixtures gas should be positioned compared to the gas inlet position:",
    answers: ["never higher than the gas-inlet;",
    "on the same level;",
    "always lower than the gas-inlet;",
    "always higher than the gas-inlet."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The reason for corrosion resistance of stainless steels is that a protective oxide film is created on the surface. This film is created by:",
    answers: ["nickel and chromium;",
    "chromium and oxygen;",
    "nickel an oxygen;",
    "carbon and oxygen."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Discolouring of welds in stainless steels gives an indication of loss of corrosion resistance. What has to be done to improve this situation?",
    answers: ["The discolouring is due to an oxidation at high temperature. This oxide protects against corrosion.",
    "The weld shall be polished or pickled.",
    "The weld needs only to be brushed thoroughly with a stainless steel brush.",
    "the weld shall be painted with a shop primer."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which welding processes are suitable for welding of aluminium?",
    answers: ["111 and 135.",
    "111 and 136.",
    "131 and 141.",
    "135 and 136."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which welding processes are suitable for welding of aluminium?",
    answers: ["MMA(SMAW) and MAG welding.",
    "MMA(SMAW) and FCAW.",
    "MIG welding and OAW.",
    "MIG welding and FCAW."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Welding aluminium. One of the typical imperfections is:",
    answers: ["porosity;",
    "aluminium inclusions;",
    "copper inclusions;",
    "misalignment."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which filler metal should be used for TIG-welding of AlMg3?",
    answers: ["Al 99,5 or Al 99,9.",
    "AlSi5.",
    "only AlMg3.",
    "AlMg3 or AlMg5."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is by definition the minimum chromium content in stainless steels?",
    answers: ["8%.",
    "10,5%.",
    "15%.",
    "18%."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The heat input for welding austenitic stainless steels shall be kept as low as possible, in order to:",
    answers: ["avoid burn-through occurrence;",
    "ensure grain refinement of the weld metal;",
    "minimise the time at the interval 600 °C to 900 °C (chromium-carbide formation!);",
    "avoid excessive penetration (remember: they have low thermal conductivity!)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Is it possible to weld aluminium with spray arc in \"\"difficult\"\" positions?\"",
    answers: ["No, only PA is possible.",
    "No, the weld pool is too fluid.",
    "Yes, but only thick plates.",
    "Yes, but only using FCAW."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A non-alloy steel typically includes:",
    answers: ["only iron and carbon;",
    "iron, carbon, manganese, silicon and, as impurities, sulphur and phosphorus;",
    "only ferrite;",
    "ferrite and austenite."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Where is a hardening zone created?",
    answers: ["In the weld metal.",
    "In the heat affected zone (HAZ).",
    "In the base metal outside of HAZ.",
    "\"In the weld interface \"\"Fusion zone - HAZ\"\".\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is typical for self-shielding metal arc welding (MMA/SMAW and FCAW)?",
    answers: ["The tubular electrode and the covered electrode produce a slag ensuring a complete protection of the weld pool zone.",
    "The tubular electrode and the covered electrode produce a shielding gas ensuring a weld pool zone complete protection.",
    "The flux of the tubular cored electrode and the covered electrode coating produce a slag and a shielding gas ensuring a complete protection of the weld pool zone.",
    "The flux of the tubular cored electrode and the covered electrode coating contain deoxidizers (Mn and Si) that ensure a complete protection of the weld pool zone."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is by definition typical in the chemical composition of stainless steels?",
    answers: ["The nickel content is at least 3%.",
    "There are no iron in the steel.",
    "The nickel content is at least 8%.",
    "The chromium content is at least 10,5%."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which symbol of the covered electrode designation describes all welding positions according to ISO 2560?",
    answers: ["1",
    "2",
    "3",
    "4"],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A dissimilar joint between non alloy steel and stainless steel:",
    answers: ["is not possible;",
    "is possible using a filler metal for the non-alloy steel;",
    "is possible using a filler metal for the stainless steel;",
    "is possible using a filler metal with a special composition for this purpose."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which type of filler materials is generally recommended for welding of stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Undermatching.",
    "Overmatching.",
    "The chemical composition shall be as close as possible to the parent material.",
    "Undermatching for the root run and overmatching for the top run."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Excessive electrode inclination when TIG welding (GTAW) would result in:",
    answers: ["excessive penetration;",
    "longer weld pool;",
    "tungsten inclusions;",
    "higher heat input."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Excessive electrode inclination when TIG welding (GTAW) would result in:",
    answers: ["excessive penetration;",
    "worse shielding;",
    "tungsten inclusions;",
    "higher heat input."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What does dilution refer to when cladding is involved?",
    answers: ["The mixing of parent metal with the cladding.",
    "The penetration of the cladding metal to the parent metal.",
    "The melted area of the parent metal.",
    "The cross-section of the cladding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The recommended procedure for welding on 50 mm thick clad steel is:",
    answers: ["to alternate each run from the clad to steel side and vice versa;",
    "to weld the steel side first;",
    "to weld the clad side first;",
    " to weld the thinner side first."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The material that requires the lowest heat input for welding because of its poor thermal conductivity is:",
    answers: ["mild steel;",
    "brass;",
    "aluminium;",
    "copper."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Annealing is a heat treatment process which leaves the metal in what state? ",
    answers: ["Softest, toughest, weakest state.",
    "Hardest, toughest, strongest state.",
    "Softest, toughest, strongest state.",
    "Hardest, weakest, toughest state."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What does hardness in the heat-affected zone in welding of unalloyed steel depend upon?",
    answers: ["Cooling rate.",
    "Heating rate.",
    "Chemical composition of the filler material used.",
    "Chemical composition of the shielding gas used."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What happens if, in MAG welding (GMAW) of unalloyed structural steel, heat input is reduced?",
    answers: ["The grain size in the heat affected zone increases.",
    "The risk of the occurrence of lack of fusion increases.",
    "The width of the heat affected zone increases.",
    "The risk of hot cracking in the heat affected zone increases."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What happens if, in MAG welding (GMAW) of unalloyed structural steel, heat input is increased?",
    answers: ["The grain size in the heat affected zone increases.",
    "The risk of cold cracking increases.",
    "The hardness of the heat affected zone metal increases.",
    "The hardness of the weld metal increases."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following factors influences the grain growth in a certain area of the heat affected zone of a carbon steel joint?",
    answers: ["The carbon equivalent.",
    "The chemical composition of the filler material.",
    "The temperature to which the heat affected zone was heated.",
    "Basically, the heating and cooling rates."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How could a grain size in the heat affected zone of a carbon steel joint be reduced?",
    answers: ["By preheating.",
    "By reducing heat input.",
    "By reducing the carbon equivalent.",
    "By slow cooling after welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following elements has the main influence regarding the hot cracking susceptibility:",
    answers: ["Pb",
    "S",
    "O2",
    "H2"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The susceptibility to cold cracking is minimized:",
    answers: ["when the T8/5 value is low;",
    "for weld joints with a high level of the assembly stiffness to prevent crack opening;",
    "for steels with a carbon equivalent lower than 0,35%;",
    "when the heat input, due to the preheat and postheat application, is minimized."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hot cracking in weldments:",
    answers: ["occurs if the weld deposit has a very brittle microstructure;",
    "is only related with an unfavourable chemical composition of the weld deposit;",
    "occurs if the weld joint has residual stresses and a high content of diffusible hydrogen;",
    "occurs if the base metal has a not controlled content of sulphur (S), there are tensile stresses on the weld run, and there is not enough content of Mn on the weld deposit."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"Why is it recommended to make a transition (slope) on the thicker plate if you need to make a butt joint of plates with different thicknesses?",
    answers: ["To avoid introducing defects during welding.",
    "To avoid fillet welds.",
    "To ensure full penetration of the weld.",
    "To reduce the stress concentration caused by a sudden change in thicknesses."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is it recommended to make a transition (slope) on the thicker plate if you need to make a butt joint of plates with different thicknesses?",
    answers: ["To avoid introducing defects during welding.",
    "To avoid fillet welds.",
    "To ensure full penetration of the weld.",
    "To shift the stress concentration away from the welded joint."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is it recommended to make a transition (slope) on the thicker plate if you need to make a butt joint of plates with different thicknesses?",
    answers: ["To avoid introducing defects during welding.",
    "To avoid fillet welds.",
    "To ensure full penetration of the weld.",
    "To allow an aligned weld to be performed."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The presence of notches in a steel structure can:",
    answers: ["facilitate crack propagation under static loading;",
    "cause corrosion;",
    "worsen the aesthetics of structures;",
    "reduce the yield strength of the material."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The presence of notches in a steel structure can:",
    answers: ["facilitate crack propagation under static loading;",
    "cause brittle fracture;",
    "worsen the aesthetics of structures;",
    "reduce the yield strength of the material."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"During a multi-pass welding of Y-groove butt steel plates by the MAG welding process with spray transfer, lack of penetration and lack of fusion between passes were observed. What modification would you propose in the procedure to avoid these defects in the next welds?",
    answers: ["The use of short-circuiting metal transfer mode.",
    "The use of globular metal transfer mode.",
    "To increase the welding current and welding speed proportionally.",
    "To reduce the CO2 content in the shielding gas mixture in favour of argon."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"During a multi-pass welding of Y-groove butt steel plates by the MAG welding process with spray transfer, lack of penetration and lack of fusion between passes were observed. What modification would you propose in the procedure to avoid these defects in the next welds?",
    answers: ["The use of short-circuiting metal transfer mode.",
    "The use of globular metal transfer mode.",
    "To increase the groove angle.",
    "To reduce the CO2 content in the shielding gas mixture in favour of argon."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"During a multi-pass welding of Y-groove butt steel plates by the MAG welding process with spray transfer, lack of penetration and lack of fusion between passes were observed. What modification would you propose in the procedure to avoid these defects in the next welds?",
    answers: ["The use of short-circuiting metal transfer mode.",
    "The use of globular metal transfer mode.",
    "To reduce the root face height.",
    "To reduce the CO2 content in the shielding gas mixture in favour of argon."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"This is a fatigue improvement technique:",
    answers: ["Needle peening;",
    "MIG dressing;",
    "Laser dressing;",
    "Surfacing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"This is a fatigue improvement technique:",
    answers: ["Hammer peening; ",
    "MIG dressing;",
    "Laser dressing;",
    "Surfacing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"This is a fatigue improvement technique:",
    answers: ["Grinding;",
    "MIG dressing;",
    "Laser dressing;",
    "Surfacing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"This is a fatigue improvement technique:",
    answers: ["TIG dressing;",
    "MIG dressing;",
    "Laser dressing;",
    "Surfacing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"This is a fatigue improvement technique:",
    answers: ["Vibration stress relief;",
    "MIG dressing;",
    "Laser dressing;",
    "Surfacing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Notches in a metal structure should be avoided as:",
    answers: ["they facilitate crack propagation under static loading;",
    "they reduce fatigue strength.",
    "they worsen the aesthetics of structures;",
    "they reduce the yield strength of the material."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What types of stress can cause buckling in metal structures?",
    answers: ["Tensile, compression and torsional stresses.",
    "Tensile, compression and bending stresses.",
    "Tensile, torsional and bending stresses.",
    "Compressive, torsional and bending stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"If the size of a fillet weld is not specified, a guide to weld size is:",
    answers: ["face of fillet weld is 2 times material thickness;",
    "leg length is equal to thickness of thinnest member;",
    "root penetration should be 1.5 times base metal;",
    "root to toe distance should be less than material thickness."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What base metal discontinuity results from the improper practice of rolling steel?",
    answers: ["Lamination.",
    "Delamination.",
    "Slag inclusion.",
    "High hardness."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"A jigging device will:",
    answers: ["prevent all shrinkage during tacking;",
    "completely control all distortion;",
    "promote an accurate, uniform product;",
    "prevent any elastic deformation during welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"A jigging device will:",
    answers: ["allow the welder to work harder and increase his output;",
    "speed up the fitting and welding process;",
    "prevent any elastic deformation during welding;",
    "prevent all shrinkage during tacking."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The distortion in a butt joint may be reduced by:",
    answers: ["changing from double V-preparation to double U-preparation;",
    "increasing the heat input;",
    "depositing short welds, using the backstep welding technique;",
    "increasing the number of runs."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The distortion in a butt joint may be reduced by:",
    answers: ["changing from double V-preparation to double U-preparation;",
    "increasing the heat input;",
    "decreasing the number of runs;",
    "increasing the number of runs."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The welder can reduce the shrinkage by:",
    answers: ["increasing the number of runs.",
    "decreasing the number of runs.",
    "increasing the welding speed.",
    "decreasing the welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the reasons for the discontinuity known as misalignment observed after welding is:",
    answers: ["Excessively high current.",
    "Wrong joint fit-up.",
    "Excessively high welding speed.",
    "Excessively low welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Crater cracks are mainly the result of:",
    answers: ["lack of the metal in the craters.",
    "poor joint design or joint preparation.",
    "wrong welding process used.",
    "poor shielding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Inclusions in welded joints can be:",
    answers: ["only metallic (non-metallic rise to the weld surface);",
    "only non-metallic, e.g., slag (metallic ones dilute in the weld metal);",
    "metallic and non-metallic;",
    "metallic, non-metallic and dirt."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The thick white smoke produced when arc welding galvanized steel is composed of:",
    answers: ["zinc acid fumes;",
    "galvanized smoke;",
    "zinc oxide fumes;",
    "brass oxide fumes."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Where do you want the wind to be coming from if you are fighting a fire?",
    answers: ["Wind direction is not important in fighting fires.",
    "From my side.",
    "From my front.",
    "Behind me."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 111 P BW W01 B t09 PF ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, SMAW/MMA welding, plates, butt weld, carbon steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, MAG welding, plates, butt weld, fine-grain structural steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, TIG welding, plates, butt weld, non-alloy steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, TIG welding, plates, fillet weld, non-alloy steel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 111 P BW W01 B t09 PF ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, basic type electrodes, material thickness = 9 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, rutile type electrodes, material thickness = 9 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, basic type electrodes, material thickness = 9 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, cellulosic type electrodes, material thickness = 9 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 111 P BW W01 B t09 PF ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, vertical upwards position.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, vertical downwards position.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, flat position.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, overhead position."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 111 P BW W01 B t09 PF ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, single side welding, without backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, single side welding, with backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, welding from both sides, without backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, single side welding, without backing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 135 P BW W11 t06 PC ss mb designation\"\"?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, MAG welding, plate, butt weld, stainless steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, MIG welding, plate, butt weld, fine-grain structural steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, TIG welding, plate, butt weld, non-alloy steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, TIG welding, plate, fillet weld, non-alloy steel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 135 P BW W11 t06 PC ss mb designation\"\"?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, material thickness = 6 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld without filler metal, material thickness = 6 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld without filler metal, material thickness = 6 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld with filler metal, material thickness = 6 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 135 P BW W11 t06 PC ss mb designation\"\"?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, horizontal position.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, vertical upwards position.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, flat position.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, overhead position."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 135 P BW W11 t06 PC ss mb designation\"\"?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, single side welding, with backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, single side welding, without backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, welding from both sides, without backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, single side welding, without backing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"About Visual Inspection, it can be said:",
    answers: ["It has a high cost, as the Visual Welding Inspection Kit is very expensive;",
    "It is used to identify surface discontinuities or geometric nonconformities;",
    "It requires great skill and experience from the inspector, as there are no defined acceptability criteria;",
    "In the visual inspection it is possible to observe the surface with the naked eye or with the aid of a magnifying glass or even with X-Rays with the projection on a screen."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"About Visual Inspection, it can be said:",
    answers: ["It has a high cost, as the Visual Welding Inspection Kit is very expensive;",
    "It can be performed directly or remotely (using auxiliary instruments for remote viewing);",
    "It requires great skill and experience from the inspector, as there are no defined acceptability criteria;",
    "In the visual inspection it is possible to observe the surface with the naked eye or with the aid of a magnifying glass or even with X-Rays with the projection on a screen."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"About Visual Inspection, it can be said:",
    answers: ["It has a high cost, as the Visual Welding Inspection Kit is very expensive;",
    "This technique is classified as a non-destructive testing, as it allows the evaluation of components without inducing any type of damage;",
    "It requires great skill and experience from the inspector, as there are no defined acceptability criteria;",
    "In the visual inspection it is possible to observe the surface with the naked eye or with the aid of a magnifying glass or even with X-Rays with the projection on a screen."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"About Visual Inspection, it can be said:",
    answers: ["It has a high cost, as the Visual Welding Inspection Kit is very expensive;",
    "Depending on the results of the visual inspection, the part can be rejected immediately without needs for other NDTs application;",
    "It requires great skill and experience from the inspector, as there are no defined acceptability criteria;",
    "In the visual inspection it is possible to observe the surface with the naked eye or with the aid of a magnifying glass or even with X-Rays with the projection on a screen."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Temperature indicating sticks are used to take:",
    answers: ["qualitative measurements of heat input;",
    "quantitative measurements of heat input;",
    "quantitative measurements of temperature;",
    "qualitative measurements of temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"To help reduce stress and cracking during the welding of cast iron, it is necessary to:",
    answers: ["peen the heat affected zone after it cools;",
    "peen the heat affected zone while hot;",
    "peen the weld deposit after it cools;",
    "peen the weld deposit while still hot."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Where should you aim the extinguisher?",
    answers: ["At the top of the flames, so the chemical can filter down through the flames.",
    "At the base of the flames, to put them out at their source",
    "Diagonally, to get the best of both above mentioned techniques.",
    "at the side of the fire, to profit from the highest extinguishing efficiency."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Welders qualified according to ISO 9606 to weld pipes of 180 mm diameter are also qualified to weld pipes of the following diameters:",
    answers: ["100 and 300 mm;",
    "50 and 200 mm;",
    "60 and 300 mm;",
    "75 and 360 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Welders qualified according to ISO 9606 to weld pipes of 100 mm diameter are also qualified to weld pipes of the following diameters:",
    answers: ["60 and 190 mm;",
    "20 and 150 mm;",
    "70 and 250 mm;",
    "100 and 300 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Welders qualified according to ISO 9606 to weld pipes of 25 mm diameter are also qualified to weld pipes of the following diameters:",
    answers: ["25 and 35 mm;",
    "10 and 30 mm;",
    "15 and 40 mm;",
    "25 and 50 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"This factor reduces the welding process operation factor, which is an important variable for a productivity analysis:",
    answers: ["the welding time out of the flat position;",
    "joint preparation time;",
    "welding with a low current;",
    "autogenous welding (without filler metal)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"This factor reduces the welding process operation factor, which is an important variable for a productivity analysis:",
    answers: ["the welding time out of the flat position;",
    "the weld cleaning time;",
    "welding with a low current;",
    "autogenous welding (without filler metal)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"This factor reduces the welding process operation factor, which is an important variable for a productivity analysis:",
    answers: ["the welding time out of the flat position;",
    "tack welding time;",
    "welding with a low current;",
    "autogenous welding (without filler metal)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding electric shock issue, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The risks of electric shock in welding are small in the work itself and greater due to the electrical installation (mains supply, sockets, etc.);",
    "Welding circuit cables do not represent any danger with regard to electric shock due to a low voltage drop in them;",
    "The voltage does not represent any danger to the human body, because the factor that causes the electric shock is the current;",
    "Wood is the best dielectric and is widely used in arc welding as a means of protection against electric shock."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding electric shock issue, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["Basically, it is the voltage that causes the electric shock, because the higher it is, the easier it overcomes the dielectric barrier of the human body and conducts the current;",
    "Welding circuit cables do not represent any danger with regard to electric shock due to a low voltage drop in them;",
    "The voltage does not represent any danger to the human body, because the factor that causes the electric shock is the current;",
    "Wood is the best dielectric and is widely used in arc welding as a means of protection against electric shock."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Temperature indicating sticks should be used ...",
    answers: ["when you want to know the temperature of the workpiece;",
    "to qualify a WPS as it allows for accurate recording;",
    "when you want to control the temperature within a range and for this it is necessary to use two temperature indicating sticks with the minimum and maximum temperatures of the range;",
    "when you want to accurately verify the stress relief heat treatment temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the most common type of non-destructive testing?",
    answers: ["liquid penetrant testing.",
    "Magnetic particles testing.",
    "Ultrasonic testing.",
    "Visual inspection."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"}]
    
    